CRAIG T. CHOSNEY

Portfolio: ctchosney.github.io
ctchosney@gmail.com

Phone: 740-973-4331 **Area:** Brooklyn, NY 11222

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly motivated and detail-oriented analyst with a passion for using data to improve business performance and constituent experience. Graduate work focus on quantifying the efficacy of DEI initiatives in the HR and employment sector. Expert team leadership, planning, and organizational skills developed during successful hospitality career.

WORK HISTORY

Freelance - Data Analytics Consultant

New York, NY • 09/2022 - Current

- Partnered with non-profit HR clients to assist in EEO reporting, HRIS analytics, and leveraging ADP Workforce Now for efficient data management and compliance.
- Conducted comprehensive data analysis to identify trends and insights, developed customized dashboards and reports, contributing to strategic decision-making and improved operations.
- Created and implemented data-driven instructional strategies for tutoring service Mathchops, resulting in a 25% improvement in student performance metrics.

Freemans Restaurant - Manager and Captain

New York, NY • 08/2012 - Current

- Handled customer complaints professionally, resolving issues through diplomatic acknowledgment and commitment to service, resulting in a 20% positive increase in Resy analytics customer ratings.
- Delivered in-depth training to workers in customer-facing roles to promote strong team performance.

| PROJECTS

"Minority Representation in Museum Sector Employment, 2014-2020"

- Compiled, cleaned, and manipulated EEO-1 survey data in R for proper handling.
- Developed polished visualizations to share results.

"Measuring Factors for Museum Sector Income Inequality, 2016-2021"

- Compiled, cleaned, and manipulated IPUMS USA ACS data and ran statistical analyses within STATA, including linear and logistic regressions, to process datasets.
- Tested and validated models for accuracy of predictions in outcomes of interest.

EDUCATION

CUNY Graduate Center. New York, NY • Coursework complete 5/2024, Degree 12/2024

Master of Science: Quantitative Methods and Data Analytics

Advanced Certificate: Data Science

Coursera. Online • 08/2023

Certificate: Google Data Analytics

New York University. New York, NY • 05/2022

Certificate: Computer Science, Tandon School of Engineering Preparatory Course

Parsons School of Design. New York, NY12/2007

Associate of Applied Science: Marketing And Communication

Denison University. Granville, OH

• 05/2005

Bachelor of Arts: Sociology/ Anthropology/Geology

SKILLS

- Data Visualization: Flourish, R Studio/ ggplot2, Matplotlib, Tableau
- Modeling: linear regression, logistic regression
- Programming: C++, Python, R, STATA
- Statistical analysis

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

- Big Data Analytics
- Data Mining
- Data Visualization
- Machine Learning
- Quantitative Research Methods
- Sociological Statistics
- Simulation and Modeling Techniques